# Kartavya Saini

LinkedIn: <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/kartavya99/">https://www.linkedin.com/in/kartavya99/</a> | GitHub: <a href="https://github.com/kartavya99/">https://github.com/kartavya99/</a> | Portfolio: <a href="https://portfolioks.vercel.app/">https://portfolioks.vercel.app/</a>

Phone: +61 410742021 | Email: kartavyas@gmail.com | Melbourne, AU

#### SUMMARY:

Full stack web developer leveraging a background in sales and marketing to provide the best user experience for web application development. Obtained a certificate in Full Stack Web Development from the Monash University's intensive 24-week coding boot camp. Adaptive problem-solver who loves to develop apps with focus on mobile-first design and development. Strengths in adaptability, detail-orientation, creativity, communication, problem-solving, teamwork, time-management, leadership, perseverance, and building projects from concept to completion.

### **TECHNICAL SKILLS:**

#### Languages:

JavaScript, CSS3, HTML5, SQL, NoSQL

#### **Application:**

React, MongoDB, MySQL, MVC, Third Party APis, Object Oriented Programming/Design(OOP), Object Relational Programming (ORM), Progressive Web Applications (PWA), TDD, Redux, NodeJS, ExpressJS, JSON, BootStrap

#### Tools:

Git, Heroku, MS Office.

# **Productivity:**

Slack, Microsoft Office Suits, Zoom

## **PROJECTS:**

# Ecommerce-website | GITHUB - repo | DEPLOYED - live

- **Summary:** A full stack web application build with MERN stack, where business can list their products for marketing and advertising purpose
- Tools: MongoDb, Express, React, NodeJs

# Together Fitness | GITHUB - repo | DEPLOYED - live

- <u>Summary</u>: Using Together Fitness users can search through the list of workouts and can choose the workout with its location plus users can create workout
- <u>Tools</u>: Node.js, Express, Sequelize, MySQL, JAWSDB, Heroku, Query, Bootstrap, Dotenv, BCrypt Hash Password, Geolocation API, Google Place API

# Search it | GITHUB - repo | DEPLOYED - live

- **Summary:** A search based web application which will allow the user to gain information in the form of videos and data
- Tools: YouTube API, Wikipedia API, HTML, CSS, JavaScript

# Tech Blog | GITHUB - repo | DEPLOYED - live

- **Summary:** Platform for users to create different posts, updated and delete. User can also add and comments to posts as well. User Authentication is used for security purpose as well.
- Tools: JavaScript, Node, Express, Sequelize, mysql2

#### **EXPERIENCE:**

**Dnata Catering**, Melbourne, AU - International Consolidator **January 2022 – November 2024** 

- Responsible for ensuring in-flight meals for Qantas international flights
- Achieved Quality and Quantity standards as per flight requirements.

# **Ultra Scrap Metal,** Melbourne, AU - Director **June 2017 -August 2020**

- Built a scrap metal trading business specialized in different Stainless Steel grades.
- Succeeded in purchasing container loads from different scrap yards and supplying to foundries and mills in India.

# TNT Express NZ Itd, Auckland, NZ - Account Manager July 2015- Jan 2017

- Managed geographical territory worth \$4 million NZD per annum.
- Enhanced customer base of geographical territory worth \$4 million NZD per annum by up selling, cross selling or acquiring new business.

## **EDUCATION:**

**Monash University, Melbourne** - Full-Stack Web Development Certificate Link to certificate - <a href="Link">Link</a>

The Complete JavaScript Course 2023: From Zero to Expert Link to certificate - <a href="Link">Link</a>

**Alliance Francaise, India-** Diploma in French language French language

**Gujarat University, India-** Bachelor of Commerce Advance Accounting and Auditing